theoceancleanup.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy and Cookie Notice | The Ocean Cleanup

This is the Privacy and Cookie Notice (Notice) of [theoceancleanup.com](https://theoceancleanup.com/) (Website). This Notice provides information on the processing of personal data of the visitors of the Website and persons who donate via the Website (Users) of Stichting The Ocean Cleanup, located at Batavierenstraat 15, 4-7th floor, 3014 JH, Rotterdam, The Netherlands (Foundation).

The Notice may be changed over time. Users of the Website are advised to regularly review the Notice for possible changes. The Notice was last changed on 12 December 2019.

**WHEN IS THIS PRIVACY NOTICE APPLICABLE?**  
This Notice is applicable to the processing of all personal data of Users through the Website.

**WHO IS THE CONTROLLER OF YOUR DATA?**  
The Foundation is the controller for the processing of your personal data. The Foundation may pass your information to, or allow access to such information to its subsidiaries, which are all located at the above-mentioned address, in order that they may process your personal information in the same way as the Foundation processes your personal information.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

**1\. To administer your role as a job applicant or volunteer**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
The Foundation performs extensive research and development in the fields of engineering, oceanography, economics, recycling, maritime law and more.  
You may apply for a specific job opening or send us an open application in which case we will process and store your data in order to administer the job application process.  
In addition, the Foundation is always looking for volunteers willing to offer their support. If you choose to register, the Foundation will store and process personal data, to administer your volunteer role and for communication regarding your volunteering position.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
In order to process your registration as a job applicant or volunteer and to contact you about your role, the Foundation processes data such as your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, educational background, abilities, availability, skills, and other cv information, as well as correspondence relating to your registration. If you wish to update your data or withdraw from the registration process, you can do so by contacting us via our [contact form](https://theoceancleanup.com/contact/).

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
Should your application be refused, we will retain information relating to your job application no longer than is necessary for the processing purposes and in any case no longer than **two months** after your application process has been completed. If you become a volunteer, your data will be retained no longer than is necessary for the processing purposes and in any case no longer than **two years** after your volunteer role ends. If you become an employee of the Foundation or one of its affiliates, we will process your data in accordance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as well as the applicable Dutch legislation.

**2\. For sending you information about job openings and volunteer positions**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
If you have sent us an open application for a job or registered as a volunteer, we would like to retain your application so that we are able to update you on our latest vacancies. We may do this by means of e-newsletters or by approaching you directly.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?  
_For this purpose, we process your name, address, e-mail address, educational background, abilities, availability, skills, and other cv information as well as correspondence relating to your registration and a record of which e-newsletters we have sent you.

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
We retain your personal data for as long as you wish to receive information from the Foundation. In case you no longer wish to receive such information, you can opt out at any time by contacting us via our [contact form](https://theoceancleanup.com/contact/).

**3\. For following up on your inquiries**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
On the Website, you can submit general enquires to The Foundation via our [contact page](https://theoceancleanup.com/contact/) as well as via funding(@)theoceancleanup.com. If your inquiries are related to the Plastic Journey campaign, you can submit these enquires to The Foundation via our Plastic Journey [contact form](https://products.theoceancleanup.com/pages/contact-us). You can submit media inquiries about the Foundation to the private limited company CFF Communications, a corporate and financial communications firm located in Amsterdam, via press(@)theoceancleanup. Please see CFF Communications’ privacy and cookie statement (<https://cffcommunications.nl/privacy-cookie-statement/>) for further details.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose we and/or CFF Communications process your name, your contact information, your correspondence with the Foundation about your inquiry and all other personal data you provide us with and which is required to follow up on your inquiry.

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
We retain your data as long as is necessary to follow up on your inquiry completely, with the exception of a log file with your name, contact information, the date you contacted us and the subject of your question.

**4\. For following up on your input and ideas you submit to us**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
You can submit technological ideas on cleaning the ocean to us via the Technology Input page on our website.

_Which personal data do we use for this purpose?_  
We process your name, your contact information, your correspondence with the Foundation about your input and all other personal data you provide us with which is required to follow up on your input.

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
Your data will be retained together with your input and will not be retained longer than is necessary for the processing purposes and in any case for a maximum period of 10 years.

**5\. Processing your data for donations**  
You can support us in the largest cleanup in history with your online donations. There are two types of donations you can make; a general donation through the Website (to help us continue our research, improve our technology and accelerate the largest cleanup in the history) and a donation to specifically support the Plastic Journey campaign through [product.theoceancleanup.com] to take part in the journey from pollution to products, and ultimately help us remove more plastic from the oceans.

You can make donations to two registered foundations; Euros are donated to Stichting the Ocean Cleanup (an ANBI foundation registered in the Netherlands) and US Dollars are donated to the The Ocean Cleanup North Pacific Foundation (a 501(c)(3) not-for-profit foundation registered in the USA, (TOCNPF)).

You can get detailed information on how we will process your personal data to process your donation below:

**5.1 For processing your general donation(s)**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
Via the Website, you can submit a general donation form for your general donation(s). The donations made in Euros via the Website are donated to the Foundation and such donations are subject to the [Donations Terms and Conditions](https://theoceancleanup.com/support/donation-terms-and-conditions/). The donations made in US Dollars via the Website are donated to the TOCNPF and such donations are subject to the [Donations Terms and Conditions](https://theoceancleanup.com/donate/donation-terms-and-conditions-usd/). We will use the personal data you provide to process your donation(s), follow up on your inquiries concerning your donation(s), to thank you for your support, and to fulfil our legal obligations as a foundation regarding your donation(s).

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we process your name, address (sharing your address with us is optional unless it is required for processing your donation), e-mail address, payment details, billing address (if this information is required for your region), correspondence with the Foundation or TOCNPF about your inquiries concerning your donation(s) and all other personal data you provide us with and which is required to follow up on your inquiries.

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
Based on legal obligations we retain the relevant data until seven years after you stop donating.

**5.2 For processing your donation(s) made via[products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/)**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
Via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/), you can submit a donation form for your donation(s). The donations made in Euros via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/) are donated to the Foundation and such donations are subject to the [Donations Terms and Conditions](https://products-eu.theoceancleanup.com/pages/terms-and-conditions) The donations made in US Dollars via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/) are donated to the TOCNPF and such donation(s) are subject to the [Donations Terms and Conditions](https://products.theoceancleanup.com/pages/terms-and-conditionshttps://products.theoceancleanup.com/pages/terms-and-conditions). We will use the personal data you provide to process your donation(s), follow up on your inquiries concerning your donation(s), to thank you for your support, allow you to make use of the benefits that arise from your donation(s), and to fulfil our legal obligations as a foundation regarding your donation(s).

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we process your name, address (sharing your address with us is optional unless it is required for processing your donation), e-mail address or phone number, IP address, payment details, billing address (if this information is required for your region), correspondence with the Foundation or TOCNFP about your inquiries concerning your donation(s) and all other personal data you provide us with and which is required to follow up on your inquiries.

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
Based on legal obligations we retain the relevant data until seven years after you stop donating.

**6\. For creating a Plastic Journey account**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
After making a donation via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/), you can create a Plastic Journey account to get an early access to behind-the-scenes content, and to manage and control your donation(s) that are made via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/).

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we process your name, e-mail address, payment details, billing address (if this information is required for your region), details of the donation(s) you have made via [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/).

_For what period do we retain your personal data for this purpose?_  
We retain your personal data for as long as you have a Plastic Journey account. If you delete your account, we still may need to keep the data relevant to the other purposes mentioned in this Notice. In that case, your data will be kept for the period mentioned under the relevant purpose.

**7\. If you participate in The Ocean Cleanup events, to administer your participation**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
If you participate in The Ocean Cleanup events, we will process your data to be able to organize the event, to announce participants and to measure the response to the events. We can send you e-mails to keep you updated about the event.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we use your name, address, e-mail address and any other relevant information you share with us in relation to the event.

_For what period do we retain your personal data?_  
We store your personal data until after the event. We will communicate the exact retention period per activity.

**8\. Sending you information about the Foundation by e-mail**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
We would like to keep you updated on our latest vacancies, events, developments, news items and other opportunities and developments within the Foundation. We will do this by means of e-newsletters. If you would like to stay informed on these topics, you can indicate this by subscribing through the button on our Website.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we process your name, your e-mail address and a record of which e-newsletters we have sent you.

_For what period do we retain your personal data?_  
We retain your personal data for as long as you wish to receive information from the Foundation. In case you no longer want to receive such e-mails, you can unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe option included in each e-mail.

**9\. Sending you information on the Plastic Journey by e-mail**

_What does this purpose entail?_  
We would like to keep you updated on the Plastic Journey and give you the opportunity to watch the plastic transform from pollution to product. We will do this by means of e-mails. If you would like to stay informed on these topics, you can indicate this by subscribing through the sign-up button on [products.theoceancleanup.com](http://products.theoceancleanup.com/).

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
For this purpose, we process your e-mail address and a record of which e-mails we have sent you.

_For what period do we retain your personal data?  
_We retain your personal data for as long as you wish to receive information on the Plastic Journey. In case you no longer want to receive such e-mails, you can unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe option included in each e-mail.

**10\. For the development and improvement of our Website**  
_What does this purpose entail?_  
We perform research into our User’s visit and click behavior through statistical analysis. We use the results of such research to better understand how you interact with our services, to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on our services, and to customize and improve our services. For this purpose we also use cookies.

_Which personal data do we process for this purpose?_  
We process technical data such as links clicked on, web pages visited and the browser you have used. We retain this data in aggregated form so that we can monitor general trends in the use of the Website over a period of time.

_For what period do we retain your personal data?_  
For personal data retained by cookies, see below. When your personal data is aggregated to show general trends or usage, it is anonymized and therefore no longer treated as personal data.

**WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR DATA?**  
The Foundation uses third parties for the processing of certain data, such as Website hosting, communications and payment processing. As far as these third parties have access to personal data in order to execute this kind of data processing, the Foundation has taken the required organizational and contractual measures to ensure that your personal data is exclusively processed for the purposes mentioned above. Only if the Foundation is required to do so by law, will your personal data be provided to supervisory agencies, fiscal authorities, and investigative agencies.

  * Online general donations made via the Website to the Foundation will be collected and processed by the private limited company Buckaroo B.V. (Buckaroo), an online payment provider located in Utrecht, the Netherlands. Buckaroo will gather payment details and your e-mail address, which may be used for communicating with you about payment-related matters. Please see Buckaroo’s privacy statement (<https://buckaroo.eu/privacy-statement>) for further details. Online general donations made via the Website to the TOCNPF will be collected and processed by PayPal. Please see PayPal’s privacy statement (<https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_US>) for further details.
  * Online donations made through [[product.theoceancleanup.com](http://product.theoceancleanup.com/)] (both donations to the Foundation and the TOCNPF) will be collected and processed by Shopify International Limited (Shopify), an online service and payment provider located in Ireland. Shopify will process the personal information described under 5.2 for the processing of your donation and for other purposes, including but not limited to transaction processing and fraud detection. Shopify will share the data with third parties for these purposes and may transfer the data to countries outside the EEA. Please see Shopify’s privacy policy (<https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy>) for further details.

**WHICH COOKIES DOES THE FOUNDATION USE?**  
The Website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file that we send to your internet browser so that we are able to recognize your browser when you return. Cookies can collect data on the use of the Website such as which pages are visited and the duration of a user session. When you use the Website, the cookie sends data to the Foundation or to one of our third-party service providers, such as Google Analytics or Hotjar.

  * The Foundation does not retain a cookie longer than necessary. We use session cookies and permanent cookies:  
A session cookie can track usage such as the web pages you visit and what options you use. When you close the internet browser, the session is ended and the cookie is deleted.  
A permanent cookie enables the Website to recognize you at a subsequent visit.
  * The Foundation stores cookies that are essential in providing the functionalities of the Website. For instance, the cookies enable us to customize and improve our services. You can change your browser’s settings to stop accepting cookies, or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. However, some of the Website’s features may not function properly if you disable cookies.

The Foundation also places cookies that are not strictly necessary for providing the functionalities of the Website. Through such non-strictly necessary cookies, we collect information about your use of the Website and remember your preferences. Examples of collected information are which pages are visited and the length of a user session. Through these cookies, we aim to improve your user experience of our Website. By continuing to use the Website, you consent to the use of cookies by the Foundation. If you do not consent to cookies being placed, you can block these by adjusting the settings in your browser.

**THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**  
The Website uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager and Hotjar. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Hotjar collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By using the Website, you consent to the processing of data by these third parties in accordance with their privacy policies.

**GOOGLE ANALYTICS**  
The Website uses Google Analytics’ cookies. Google Analytics is a web analysis service that is offered by Google Inc. (Google). Google Analytics uses cookies to analyze the usage of the Website by Users. Google uses aggregated statistical data to give the Foundation an insight into the way Users use the Website.  
You can find more information on Google Analytics’ Privacy policy here: <https://www.google.nl/intl/en/policies/>

**HOTJAR**  
The Website uses services provided by [Hotjar Ltd](https://docs.hotjar.com/v1.0/docs/data-safety-and-security) for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Website and compiling reports on website activity.  
Hotjar uses a variety of services hosted by third parties, such as Google Analytics and Optimizely. These services may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, such as cookies or your IP request. For information on how Google Analytics and Optimizely collect and use your information, please refer to their privacy policies. By continuing to use this Website, you consent to the processing of the above data by Hotjar and by the third parties used by Hotjar in accordance with their respective privacy policies. To opt out please go to the following link: <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out>

**HOW TO TREAT LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES AND SOCIAL MEDIA?**  
If you choose to visit one of the websites offering merchandising, such as Rapanui, Musto or Dopper, you will be directed to the respective website.

If you choose to share our Website through social media such as LinkedIn, Facebook and/or Twitter, your personal data (such as your name and the fact that you are interested in the Foundation) will also be visible to all the visitors of your personal webpage on LinkedIn, Facebook and/or Twitter.

On the use of such merchandising and social media websites, only the terms and conditions (including the privacy policy) of the merchandising or social media website apply. The Foundation is not responsible for the processing of personal data or the privacy policy of such merchandising or social media websites.

**MAY PERSONS BELOW THE AGE OF 16 PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA?**  
Persons below the age of 16 may only provide personal data to the Foundation if they have the permission of one of their parents or their legal guardian who has read this Notice.

**HOW DO WE SECURE DATA?**  
Your personal data are treated as strictly confidential and the Foundation has taken appropriate technical and organizational security measures against loss or unlawful processing of this data. To this purpose Foundation uses several security techniques including secure servers, firewalls and encryption, as well as physical safeguard of the locations where data are stored.

**WHAT ARE YOUR RIGHTS AS A DATA SUBJECT?**

You may at all times and without any cost access the data you have provided to the Foundation, you can object to the processing of your data, and, if you wish, have these data rectified or deleted.

You also have the right to data portability. If you wish to use one of these options, you can give notice thereof in writing to:

Stichting The Ocean Cleanup  
Attn: General Counsel  
Batavierenstraat 15  
4-7th floor, 3014 JH Rotterdam, The Netherlands  
You may also send an e-mail to us via our [contact form](https://theoceancleanup.com/contact/).

Finally, in addition to the rights mentioned above, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, such as the Dutch Data Protection Authority.
